<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Pique&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daniel Pique&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational resources and best practices for your PhD</title>
      <link>/2018/04/07/computational-resources-and-best-practices-for-your-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/07/computational-resources-and-best-practices-for-your-phd/</guid>
      <description>Below are some computer-related things that you need to do or know about while doing your PhD at Einstein. I have supplemented and customized this list with the resources that Einstein offers to facilitate this. The resources are a bit spread out across multiple websites, but hopefully this list helps synthesize these different resources.
Below are some computational resources offered by Einstein, along with people you should get in touch with to obtain these resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to access and work on Einstein&#39;s HPC cluster</title>
      <link>/2017/11/29/introduction-to-einstein-s-hpc-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/29/introduction-to-einstein-s-hpc-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Request access to the cluster. This can be done by emailing Brent Solly or Shailesh Shenoy and asking to be added as a user. An account and userid will be created for you. You can also submit a ticket through the IT support portal to request account access.
 Open up a terminal (Mac/Linux) or command prompt (Windows)
 In the prompt, type ssh user_id@ip_address, where user_id is your montefiore ID/username, and ip_address is the IP address shared with you by the IT team (should start with the number 10 and be in the following format: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>logit</title>
      <link>/2017/11/28/logit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/28/logit/</guid>
      <description>logit(p) &amp;lt;- log(p/(1-p)) #this is appropriately called the log odds. The “odds” are a ratio between 2 events – the probability of the event happening (p) and not happening (1-p). We see this as p/(1-p). The odds are wrapped in a logarithm – hence the log-odds.
It is used to transform probabilities on the open interval (0,1) to the Real number line.
The distribution of many of these mapped probability values is often assumed to have a Normal distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principal Component Analysis</title>
      <link>/2017/11/24/principal-component-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/24/principal-component-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this tutorial is to understand PCA and to be able to carry out the basic visualizations associated with PCA in R. What is the purpose of PCA? In two words: dimensionality reduction. Basically, we use linear algebra to transform the original variables into a new set of variables called Principal Components (PCs). The number of original observations and variables stays the same, but the new variables are ordered by how much variance they explain in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Thank you for visiting my site!
I develop tools to gain insights into cancer from high-throughput genomics sequencing data. I am currently an MD/PhD student at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine (Bronx, NY) in the Department of Systems and Computational Biology. I am interested in the application of machine learning methods to high-throughput sequencing data to identify novel oncogenes and drug targets in cancer. I am also interested in streamlining patients&amp;rsquo; visits to medical clinics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/1/01/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/</guid>
      <description>How to access and work on Einstein’s HPC cluster      h1 { font-size: 34px; } h1.title { font-size: 38px; } h2 { font-size: 30px; } h3 { font-size: 24px; } h4 { font-size: 18px; } h5 { font-size: 16px; } h6 { font-size: 12px; } .table th:not([align]) { text-align: left; }    .main-container { max-width: 940px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; } code { color: inherit; background-color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Email: daniel.pique@med.einstein.yu.edu
Education  2013–2021 (expected) MD-PhD, Systems &amp;amp; Computational Biology; Einstein (Bronx, NY)
Thesis title: Characterization of novel oncogene candidates in invasive breast carcinoma
 2008-2012 BS, Genetics; University of Georgia (Athens, GA)
Minor: Spanish
Certificate in Interdisciplinary Writing
  Publications  Pique, D., Greally, J. and Mar, J. (2017). oncomix: Identifying Genes Overexpressed in Subsets of Tumors from Tumor-Normal mRNA Expression Data. R package version 1.0.0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Below are some resources that I have found useful related to data science:
 R for Data Science
   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>